Hello hello, good evening everyone
Have you all eaten dinner?
You can post more comments
Because Christmas night...
It's not Christmas, it's Christmas night
I'm live streaming on Christmas night
I'm afraid there might be a few people watching
If everyone posts more, there will be more people
There will be more people coming to the livestream
Is that right?
Hello, my name is Silu Qingqi
Hello
Why...
Why do I have to watch livestreams when I'm on the street?
Don't do it, it's still Lang teacher
Let's go to the street
Candy
Next time
I'll post it on Valentine's Day
I'll post a little red envelope to buy candy for you
Wear a hat
Oh, you can take off your hat and sit
But...
It might be more troublesome
You might have to split it
It's...
Oh, no wonder
I got it, I got it wrong
If you're making an animation of taking off your hat
Because your hand is going to be holding the hat
So...
You need to use a needle to sew the hat onto your hand
Although it sounds cruel
But it's okay in our software
It's okay
You don't have to...
You don't have to care about the health of our virtual models
Oh, I saw a note
Hello
Let's officially start today's content
Let me introduce myself first
I'm Sherry, the designer of IZ Model
Today I'm going to explain
How to make a Christmas-themed costume
And then...
In the video
A little bit later
We'll talk about how to make an animation
Okay, let's get started
First of all, in Marvelous Designer
If you want to make an animation
You have to first
Draw the A-pose model in the form of an OBJ
This action is because
The animation we usually make
The first needle is different from the A-pose or T-pose we often use
In Marvelous Designer
If you want to achieve the change of this action
You can use two OBJ models with the same number of points
To make a change
This is called Morph Target
In addition to doing this
We can also export an FBX file
You must be thinking
Why do I import an OBJ and an FBX?
That's because
Sometimes we go directly to Maxamo
To download some action files
That is, upload our files
And then download FBX
In Maxamo
If you upload an OBJ
It doesn't have skin texture
If you upload FBX
When you download it
As long as you put it in the original FBX file
In the same folder
It will have its own skin
This is for some
Children who don't know how to make animation
You can use this Maxamo
You can steal a small basket
Or change some actions
Because you can be in a certain
Under the set number
To use this action
Okay, after that
Everyone can pay attention
When using Maxamo
You can put the arm shoulder
A little higher
In this case
Because in Marvelous Designer
If your action is this
Under the page
There is this model insertion
Or the thigh here
If there is a model insertion
There will be some problems
Your cloth
Because its cloth is
Posted outside the model
If it passes the model
To the inside of the model
It will be unstable
So if you do the action on the website
Everyone must pay attention
You don't want the body action
To have this
Pressure point
It's best to let them separate
Okay, for example
This is our first action
You can see this action
It's definitely different from A pose and T pose
So we will be in this pose
Pour the OBJ model out again
Once
Then we can
After wearing the clothes on the A pose model
Direct the OBJ
Pour it in again
Then replace it with this action
Then
Repeat some of the steps we used to do before
Is to make clothes
Because I have actually escaped
The size of this model
So our software
The size of the default costume
Is incompatible
But I
Because I thought
I just want to keep one
A collar inside
Then I will make a sweater outside
Wearing it outside
So I don't care about the shape inside
Because it's just a T-shirt inside
It's tight
Haha
Everyone in the process of using MD
Is
Can
Use this
What you can't see
Don't do
Haha
Then we make a collar
This collar version
Everyone can remember
It's almost the collar version
It's all like this
Just a little wider above
Take a little bit down below
A upside down shape
Then sew it up
Then arrange it in the model's back
Here
What about the shoulder
Pull it out from the middle of the model
Good evening everyone
You can send more chats
Because I recorded this
Live video
So maybe it looks faster
The animation of the first quilt
Can also be simulated
But what about the first quilt
Do this
Um do
Ordinary animation
It's not the same
Because you first quilt
Just as long as your hand
To drag this cloth
Then you need to pause
Then create a fake sewing needle
Then continue to record the animation at the back
You have to lead the previous animation
Or you have to take this animation
From the middle
You understand
Because the fake sewing needle
This thing
It works in time
From now on
It will work
Understand
Um
If there is a chance in the future
I can make a similar animation
Show you
But I just say
I'm not sure when
Really available
Then draw the inner line
To fold this collar
Um
This is not a recording
I am myself
It's just that this is my video
Hello hello
Ah
Ha ha
Oh
Ah
Right
Then I change this costume
Just give her a layer of cologne
Yeah
You can also send a chat
If you have any questions
Uh
What about after cologne
I'm going to start making this sweater
That sweater
It must be much wider than the body
I did the first thing
Is to put this up
Breast dimple
For men, the chest width is actually at the bottom of the night.
Make the chest width a little wider,
and make the bottom width a little wider,
so that it becomes a relatively loose one.
Then you can see here,
you can put this point at the bottom of the night,
because we normally wear a sweater,
the bottom of the night is not very tight here,
so we will pull this point and this point down.
After pulling down,
there will be a relatively loose amount here.
When we have some arm movements afterwards,
it will not have that kind of tearing feeling.
Okay?
In fact, it is mainly because the sweater is a relatively loose pattern.
If you feel that it is a little narrow,
you can continue to pull it wider.
Then generally speaking,
the characteristic of sweaters is that
there will be a relatively
tight pattern.
Because otherwise,
the sweater will not have a shape.
So we will make two rectangular shapes.
And then the sleeves,
the sleeves will also have such a rectangular shape.
Then sew them together.
Hello everyone, good evening.
First of all,
we will have a recording of this.
So if everyone now,
please help us to hold the stage.
But if you have other things to do now,
you can do other things first.
Dating is more important.
The thickness can be pulled out.
Then we will tighten the bottom a little bit.
This set of clothes is actually not too difficult,
so everyone can take a look.
Hello hello, thank you Erxun.
Thank you Erxun.
It's not.
It's still better to go out for a date.
Let me see,
what am I doing next?
I tightened the bottom a little bit.
Change some fabrics.
I changed it to a jersey fabric,
J-e-r-s-e-y fabric at the beginning.
This kind of fabric is all for sweaters,
for sweaters,
So please remember, if you want to make a sweater, just use the fabric
And here you can see that I have widened the shoulder line along the shoulder line, right?
I am 95 years old, you can calculate how old I am this year
I have widened the shoulder line along the shoulder line
Why? Because normal sweaters are not very tight, you know?
Because overall, sweaters are relatively loose. Of course, there are also tight sweaters
But today I just want to make a loose sweater for him
Generally loose clothes, the shoulders are not exactly like a vest
It will definitely be a little bigger outside
It will look more casual
You know what I mean?
It will be more loose, it will have a slender feel
In fact, as long as you remember this step, it will be fine
When you are making this kind of loose clothes, remember to make the shoulder line a little longer
Why do I have time for live streaming?
This is because I arranged it
I want to live stream today, so I will live stream today
You see, it's not that no one is dating with me
We now have 400 people
Let's assume that we have 40 people watching our live stream
Then I will be dating with 40 people at the same time, right?
Then we will freeze the big body
Because the size of our big body is ok
Then we will change the sleeves
You know
You don't have to change the clothes and the sleeves at the same time
If you change the clothes and the sleeves at the same time
Because the sheets are influenced by each other
So after you sew them together, they will be there
You can change the clothes and the sleeves at the same time
Then you just don't know if you have noticed
Our sleeves
In the past, it was in a higher position
You can move your body after you finish making clothes
It is best to use a skirt
Don't just look at the pressure
If you want to make a skirt
Or a bigger skirt
Go to see our previous video
The live stream of the last time
You know?
Good evening everyone
Hello, Dongxun and baby
Good evening
Then just now
When we were changing the clothes
You should pay attention
For example, our shoulders
Did it just get longer?
Then our sleeves
If we want the sleeve to be connected to a straight line, and there is no change in the other position,
should we pull the sleeve down as well?
Can you understand?
Because your shoulder is longer, and there is more fabric on this side, so there is less fabric on this side.
So we need to pull the top of the sleeve down.
I've been working for 4 years.
Actually it's been 5 years, I started working in our company when I was in college.
And because the bottom of the sleeve also went down,
so the two sides of the sleeve correspond to the bottom of the sleeve.
No, don't pull the sleeve up and wait for it to be simulated by itself.
You can also simulate it,
but the length doesn't change.
For example, our sleeve is pulled out,
but the bottom of the sleeve doesn't go down.
That is, there is no change in the bottom of the sleeve.
So our points correspond to each other.
In MD, the correct way to change clothes is point by point.
For example, this point goes out,
then you turn this point to this side,
it goes out, then it goes down.
Understand?
Our company doesn't have a plan yet,
but we don't know what will happen next year.
And then the next step is to make the sleeves.
To change the sleeves,
it's no different from the normal operation.
Just a little bit,
pull the sides long and wide.
Also, change the curve here to be more flat.
Another point is,
I have mentioned it to you many times,
people do the corners of the sleeves inside MD,
try to make the corners too close to the corners of the sleeves.
Add the sleeve that doesn't have a belt.
Take a look at how it goes.
I will make the lips,
the lips,
lips,
For the sleeves, when we are talking about the sleeves, I will move the sleeves up a little, so that it doesn't fall down
If you are working at the age of 16, it should be illegal, right?
At the age of 16, it's better to study well
And then there are some simple modifications, some steps for the sleeves
Hello, hello everyone, good evening
Hello, hello
It is indeed a bit boring to change clothes, but you can't say that it's not necessary, it's still necessary
So everyone, look at this part
If you look tired, you can post more chats and chat with me
Then we won't be tired, right?
I don't know if you noticed it just now, but there are often some problems in the bottom of the page
It's like the bottom of the page is clamped
If there is such a problem, is it because we have a small section here?
If we move this point directly, will it be smooth?
So are our two sides the same?
It's just a long one
If it's a long one, put it down here
Put it down here
Is it easy to tie the bandage on the arm?
It's very easy to do
It's very simple
I forgot if we had recorded the corresponding video before
But once you look online, you can find some videos of bandages in CMD
So now we will put this point on both sides in it
Today there will be a recording
There are a lot of female colleagues in our company
Super many
But it's a pity that you don't have any chance
There is no chance mainly because there are not many people
There are more people in the next room
It's okay on MD side
OK, we put the sleeve cuff on
After putting it on, we use it to fix the two fixed needles of the sleeve before
Do you usually use MD?
Some time ago, I saw that we have those
Are you here to participate in the draw?
Often
Then I see that you usually don't post works
Anyway, if you usually post works, you can add us
As long as you add us, we will help forward
Then here I am constantly changing the position of this dress
I just think that this dress is strange no matter how I wear it
Do you feel it?
I feel that the chest is very straight
But the side is a little pappa
Soft
It doesn't look very good
It's basically not the original sorry circle
It doesn't matter
If you are learning
We don't have MD official
Basically, if you are learning a certain other artist's work
You can put the artist you are learning
The video link of the artist's work
And you do this together with us
So that we can know more
Which artists are using our software
Then because I thought this before
This sweater is a little strange
It's a little too wide in the waist
So I'm changing the point of his waist
When you usually change clothes
It's best to divide the clothes into a few areas
One is the shoulder
That is, when you change it, you only change the point of the shoulder
There is another one
This is the point of the chest
This is the point of the waist
This point
Remember to break it
Don't adjust the whole waist line
It's best to adjust one point at a time
Try to avoid doing a whole line
A whole line of lines
Then actually
The sweater we wear in real life
Its side is not like this
There is a break or a bend
But it doesn't matter
In MD
It's just what you want it to look like
You can add points and then change
Then just reduce the particle diameter
And the thickness of the gap
Let's take a look at the effect after this simulation
Then
This one
Because just before I changed
I always feel that the pleats of the waist here are very strange
So in the end
I still changed this side to be
A more tight state
In fact, you just need to adjust one point at a time
To adjust a little bit
It's not very difficult to make clothes
Just change clothes yourself
But if you don't know how to change clothes
You can look at the bottom left corner
Add our QQ group
From Monday to Friday
Ten o'clock to seven o'clock
Basically there are technical support
Usually
We will also take a look at it
Is there any problem in the group
So everyone can come to our group
To ask questions
You can send more chats
You can chat with us
Something
How many meters is the current chat assistant?
50 meters
If you have any questions
If you want to chat with Jin Mi
You can also post it in the chat
I don't know how to play the board while looking at the picture
In fact
This
I don't know how to play the board while looking at the picture
There are two solutions
What about one?
You go find its size first
For example, it is a sweater
You go to the Internet
Search sweater paper
The paper is the paper of the paper
The paper of A4 paper
Then the sample is the sample of the sample
You go find its size first
Then under its size
Just find a pattern
Throw it in MD
Then change its point according to your needs
Do you know
Just don't
What is it
If you want to steal it, you can
You can also change it directly with T-shirt
But there are already a lot of existing patterns on the Internet
It will be easier to take their patterns directly
What else
You can go to our MD
On the official business city
Go first
Put down all the free ones
Then change it on the free clothes
Then I used a layer here
To deal with the outside and inside sheets
In fact, no matter what kind of clothes
You can find it in real life
Almost a little corresponding
Then on those basics
I've changed the color to make it easier for me to distinguish between the pieces.
Next, I'm going to make the pants.
There's nothing really important about making the pants,
because these are just some of the things we've talked about before,
including how to make the pants and so on.
Let's take a quick look at this.
Pink is the most common color.
Do you guys usually need to make the pants?
Do you need to make the pants?
Because in the past,
when you were making the pants,
you would feel that it was inconvenient to change the pattern, right?
Is there such a need?
Now that we have the pants,
it's very convenient to make these pleats.
Because there are actually a lot of pleats.
You're doing it in some special action.
That's why there are pleats like this.
For example, the pleats of the short skirt.
The pleats of the short skirt are not quite the same as the pleats of the short skirt.
The short skirt is tighter, but the method is similar.
You can change its movement.
Under some movements that are relatively large,
make some shapes for the pleats of the waist.
Then go back to the normal standing posture.
It won't change.
And then here.
Because I've been changing the basic pants pattern before.
What about it?
It's a little tighter.
Just like the waist side, right?
The tighter the pants, the easier it is for those pleats to appear.
Unless it's too tight.
When it's more yellowish like this,
it's easier for those pleats to appear.
Because the pleats are formed based on your strength.
The pleats are formed when you have the pulling force.
Or when you have the gravity,
the pleats are formed.
Or when you have two points of support.
Between these two points,
there will be a kind of smile.
It's like a hammer.
It's also a pleat of fabric.
The pleats.
So when you make pants,
it's easier to make pleats when it's tighter.
And when you make skirts,
it's also easier to make pleats when it's tighter.
But you have to compare our pressure pattern.
See if it's in the yellow or green area.
This area is the easiest to make pleats.
Do you understand?
If you get to that kind of red,
which is especially tight,
imagine if you pull another piece of cloth.
You've used a lot of strength to pull it apart.
Then will it be flattened by you?
Right?
So,
when you make pleats,
you have to find the right angle.
Don't pull it too tight.
And don't let it pile up there.
Sometimes,
the author is like a
snowman.
Space Mouse.
What is Space Mouse?
Unlocking the link between the pages.
It's difficult to restore the link
because you've modified some of it.
So,
unlock the link at the end.
For example,
when I make the pants,
I drew an inner line here.
The inner line here is actually useless.
Our normal door,
the front door of the pants,
pull the chain.
Then,
here,
this inner line is useful.
This inner line is useless.
I will unlock the link at the end.
Then,
delete the inner line.
The pleats need to be completely straight left and right.
Including all the inner lines
and the curve points.
They all need to be the same.
What can I do if the pants fall down
and I use a fixed needle?
For the pants,
you can use a fixed needle
to sew it on the top of the pants.
Or,
your belt needs to be tighter.
Understand?
And,
normally,
it won't fall down.
Think about it.
I made a lot of movements,
but it didn't fall down
even if I turned it over.
Normal pants
usually don't fall down.
So,
it won't fall down.
Here,
it's a door lock.
For this,
I'll show you how to do it.
If you want to keep the shape of your clothes or sleeves,
after choosing the pattern,
there is a
a
a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a
So when you are making a belt, it will often go up, and when you are making a tight top, it will fall down, which is actually one of the reasons why they are running to the thinnest position of the model.
So the main solution to this problem is that you have to widen your belt.
The reason why I didn't explain the reason for the pants is mainly because the pants are relatively simple and common.
If you have any problems with the operation or explanation later, you can wait for me to finish talking about this Christmas-style dress tonight, and then ask the questions in the answer section.
MD's sculpting and simulation has no effect.
So now we are launching a new model.
We have launched a new model, which is called Sculpting and Sculpting.
You can use a brush to brush the Sculpting and Sculpting function.
Let me show you how it works.
I don't know if this is going to work.
That is to say, for example, now we,
It should be 1,410 yuan per year
1,410 yuan per year
It's a personal version
Oh, that's right
Tonight, it's not an old man's makeup
It's...
It's from a GIF
Don't you all know what I'm doing today?
Let's demonstrate first
For example, here
I'm doing some
special creases
like this
Oops
Then I can use
Select Browse Browse
Select these creases here
Then select Format
After that
I'll start the simulation
No matter how I drag it
It won't fall apart
It will
keep 80%
of the previous
creases
I'm a costume designer
Yes
My usual job is
to do the
software support
and some
translation
and some tutorials
I do all of them
If I use a fixed needle
The point of drag is a bit rounder
It doesn't have this soft selection function
When you drag the point
your particle diameter
is relatively high
Do you understand?
Then
After I'm done with my pants
I'll change its physical shape
and change it to
Cotton Goblin
This fabric is for pants
Drag it to a point
You should not be
starting the simulation
Or you're stretching it too much
Because fixed needle
was originally a point
Its main function is
to hold the point
Not to hold it
Do you understand?
It can hold the point
But if you drag it too much
It will be a point
First of all
your particle diameter
should be smaller
Because when the particle diameter
is large
One grid point
is very large
Do you understand?
After that
Let's make the Christmas hat
It's quite simple
Draw a triangle
This is the hat
of our Christmas hat
Draw a rectangle
Fix the hat
on the head
It's soft
If you want to undo it
You can't undo it
The reason why you
want to undo it
is because
you didn't press the lock
Every time
You push the lock
you need to undo it
Everything went back
You only record once
So in the process
of undoing it
Is it too short?
Uh, yes
Then make a rectangular plate
Combine the two sides
Then make her a Christmas hat
And then because we wait a moment
Like a blue elf
That's right, a blue elf's hat is made like this
But at the end, because I added a fixing pin here
So it won't fall down
If I delete the fixing pin, it will fall down
Hello, hello, hello
Then we have to reduce the conflict thickness
Because the hat is a tight one
It will be stuck on the head
Like an Indian
A little bit like
Then use the sewing tool
Sew the hat and the hat salt together
Uh, because everyone can see
If I didn't freeze the bottom plate just now
Will it be pulled up by the top
So I will use a fixing pin
Double click on a grid top
You can add a fixing pin along the row
Then fix the fixing pin to the virtual model
Then I don't care how I move later
The top of this circle grid
It will be fixed on the model
It won't be because we are outside
To the material settlement or something
Yes, then transform
In this case, although the virtual model will hurt
But it doesn't matter
We don't care about this material
It will be fixed in this position
No matter what we do in the future
What animation or something
It won't be moved
Ah
Yes, so this is the source of gravity
Understand
Even if you
Even in our process
This model
The person is facing down
His hat won't fall down
Uh, material preview transparency out
Out 4
Yes, there will be a round ball
I will add a round ball at the end
If you are previewing transparency
Then you have a transparency setting below the fabric
It can be set there
Uh, there is a path
There is a path
What about the last ball
I will use a board here to replace it
Because uh
The ball is a copy
We will import it in the form of a copy
The copy has its own weight, right?
Then if we directly put the ball
Stick to this hat
What about the above?
Its weight is not very controllable
And sometimes it may be
Just this copy
It will
Just throw it away
That is, it will have its own gravity
Then we may be able to use a board first
To control it
Uh, MD and SP interaction
Yes
Just use the normal 3D format
Um, I feel like there are a lot of people here today
It's a friend who just started using MD
Um, if you have any questions
If you have any questions
You can also ask us at any time
In our Bilibili and QQ group
Oh, you can see that I added a
This is the elastic
Oh, just to imitate some
Some of the creases in this seam
Let's talk about Chinese
Installation is official Chinese fabric
Um
Uh
This Chinese
Official
The fabric is
There is no way to add it at the moment
There is a loop in front
There is no way to add it
The reason is because
When we install the software
Uh, this is a process of decompression
The installation bag that was built into the software at the beginning
It is
Chinese and English are put in it
It's not like
You can set this Chinese and English before you install it
So
All of our names are
English name format fabric
And
What we developed
Is in Korea
Oh, oh, oh, oh
Okay, okay
I just want to explain
Because our development is in Korea
Well, sometimes you use Chinese words
Some Chinese words
In Korea
There may be a bug
This is why we usually tell everyone
During the process of using MD
Uh
Is to
That is
Is to pay attention
It's best not to use Chinese and Chinese
It's best to avoid this kind of problem
Um
Uh, what about this fabric?
I
I recorded the video in English
Because I've always been used to using English fabric
Uh
Oh, I know
I used to use cardigan pants
That fabric is called cardigan pants
Pants
What about the hat here?
Uh, I seem to be using default fabric
Um
You can see my small square cloth at home
Then I will take this cloth
Um
I will take this transparent cloth
I will reduce the transparency
Uh
I will decrease the transparency
Then I will
Uh
What is it called?
Increase density
To imitate a
That is
A weight effect of the ball
Then I will reduce the transparency of this panel
It looks like this is the ball
Dragging this cap
In fact, it is the function of this panel
The density of this panel is higher than I mentioned
For fabric, we have a document. In the document, you can find out what it is used for.
In the previous video, you can find out what it is used for.
I have combined the front and the back.
Then I cut it out.
The purpose of combining is to
make sure that there is no seam line in the front of the board.
It can be a whole flat left symmetrical board.
You can guess why I cut out a whole strip here.
I will give you a minute to make a brain storm.
Why did I cut out a small strip here?
What am I going to do?
Let me tell you first.
I will sew that little strip later.
I will sew a rectangular board.
I will sew a rectangular board here.
Why?
Good evening, everyone.
Good night, Christmas.
The Excel table can be downloaded under that video.
It can be downloaded from Baidu.
Why?
I see that no one has replied.
Let me reply for you.
Here's the thing.
Have you noticed that?
When we are making the bottom board and the sleeve board,
we are all inclined to make a rectangular board, right?
Because when we are drawing the texture,
in MD,
when you pour it out,
the UV is directly used in MD, right?
Then our board,
you may have a rectangular one here.
The rectangular is more convenient for drawing texture.
Or if you use the texture from the outside,
it is more convenient to draw a straight line.
But just now,
is the collar here curved?
If we cut off the edge with a scissor,
is that edge curved?
If you draw your UV along this edge,
or the texture,
is it more inconvenient?
You can understand this point, right?
Because often,
the board like this,
the texture on this side is straight.
And the collar here,
there is also a circle along the collar.
We call it a spiral.
If the board is curved,
the spiral is not easy to draw.
Let me open it.
Open a project file.
Wait a moment.
Okay, okay.
Hello, good evening, everyone.
Hello.
Okay, let me see, let me see.
Then I measured its length,
drew this rectangular board,
and sewed it.
Let me see if my project file is open or not.
Oh,
for a board like this,
first of all,
we will reduce the strength of its tail.
Because,
it's going to be a small class again.
Because our board,
it is divided into the front and the back,
right?
For a board like this,
if we want to make it,
to be able to fit the width better,
we will reduce its strength of the tail,
the strength of the tail.
To reduce the strength of the tail,
it can be in this direction,
that is,
on the horizontal direction,
make some large stretches.
It will not deform,
or make some wrinkles.
In this way,
it is more convenient for us to,
just,
let it follow the bottom of this board,
to make a deformation.
Uh,
Morph,
you can't just morph to half.
You can,
because Morph,
if you have clothes,
it's okay.
If you have clothes,
in the process of Morph,
there is a pause button.
This button,
it will become a pause button.
You can pause,
but if you don't wear clothes,
it won't work.
Um,
let me take a look at this document.
This is what we did in the end.
Let's take a look at the collar here.
After I replaced it with a straight board,
you just have to do these straight lines,
but if it is a curve,
it will be more difficult to match.
Understand?
The fold line is basically not very soft.
In this version,
I added an internal line to fold in the middle.
If you want to compare the harder ones,
you have to draw this internal line to fold.
After folding,
delete this line when the particle diameter is relatively low,
and then double-click control,
do a short simulation.
Otherwise,
it will be very obvious that it will go to a point along this side.
You have to let it,
um,
go through it appropriately.
So double-click control,
do a short simulation.
Um,
let's change the progress.
Okay.
After we have the overall shape,
it's almost done.
Uh,
let's change the movement.
Before changing the movement,
you can make some final adjustments.
For example,
this pants is a little,
a little narrow.
You can make it wider.
Because I'm using the fabric of the cardigan now.
The feature of this fabric is that it can make some folds,
because it is less stretchable.
Did the official live broadcast have a draw?
Why didn't you come to the last draw?
Now,
not this time today.
There will be next time.
Later,
I will tell you about our plan for next year.
Okay?
Um,
you can pay attention to it later.
There will be a recording.
Okay.
These are some simple modifications of this pants.
Then,
if I modify the pants,
it is the same.
Divide the pants into three points.
Uh,
not every issue of next year will have it.
The user exchange conference at the beginning of next year will have it.
On January 7th or January 8th.
January 8th.
That day.
It's a Saturday afternoon.
There will be a period of cooperation between us and two artists.
In that period,
there will be a draw MD.
Okay?
It is also a draw MD license.
Um,
then,
when everyone was changing clothes,
did we just say that we divided the clothes into several pieces?
The shoulders are one piece.
Then,
the bottom of the night is our chest.
It's a piece.
And the waist.
There are these points.
As for the pants,
it's even easier.
The pants are the waist.
There is a point here.
Then,
there is a point on the knee.
Finally,
there is a point on the crotch.
So,
when everyone is changing pants,
you don't want to pull a whole piece.
You add a point here first.
Cut off the point.
Uh,
the recording,
of course,
is recorded under our ID.
That is,
in MD official.
There will be.
This recording will be uploaded next week.
You are so amazing.
Now we are live streaming.
Then,
you ask us where the recording is.
Is BDD used less?
Then,
we will import this OBJ.
This is our first stitch.
It seems to be unstable,
but it doesn't matter.
It will be fine in a while.
Uh,
first of all,
our live streaming is for
just to give you a little fun.
Ah,
it's the friends who don't have activities at night.
You can come and have a look.
Secondly,
I hope that you can focus on what we are talking about
when you are watching our live stream.
These knowledge,
not some other irrelevant content.
Um.
OK.
Yes.
So.
Then,
just a little,
after changing our live stream,
uh.
It can manually adjust the differences
in the First Stitch income.
Uhhh.
It's not for itching or fortune telling,
it's for stealing.
The reason I wanted to choose this action
was that I was thinking.
Why do everyone think
that People of Christmas are good?
Is it for giving gifts to everyone?
Can't it be for stealing gifts?
So I changed it
I made it look like a thief
It's an action of
turning the window
Because every year
Santa is carrying a bag
and giving gifts to everyone
So I wanted to make it
look like a thief
Do you know
Moftarget?
Moftarget refers to
when two virtual models
have the same number of points and faces
the actions will be changed
So just now
our virtual model
is an A-Post
I made it look like
the OBJ file
under the first action
will automatically
transform into this
A-Post
It's not hard to do
After that, I made it a big bag
Let's speed up
the process
Draw a circle
and draw a line
along the line
to make a bag
Before that
let's make a fill
Otherwise, the bag will be empty
If there is no fill in the middle
it will look empty
It will look like this person
is just carrying a bag
So let's make a small pillow
Turn the surface
and then
reduce the particle diameter
to simulate
After that
let's give this board
some pressure
After that, it will bulge
Because what I'm doing now
is facing out
So my pressure is
balanced
Both pressure values are 5
Then I put this
pillow inside
This
method I use
is quite special
Because I
want it to have
the same effect
So I add two pins
In fact, if you usually do it
You don't have to bother
Just do it separately
I might have done it
for Tola
I just thought
It doesn't matter
Let's do these two together
After that, I can just simulate
and put this pillow
in my small bag
In the big bag
In the end, I found that it didn't work
This is after I added
the spring
After I added the spring
Let's print the board
I added a pin
to prevent it from falling
under the ground
As long as I add the spring
to the middle of the circle
It will close
the hole
After that
I can zoom in
to make it a bigger bag
Then I can
give it some pressure
After I added the pressure
to 10
This bag becomes
a more solid bag
You must be thinking
Since this bag
looks solid
Why do you need to put the pillow
inside?
This is because
during the animation
The material's properties will have an external impact
It will move
along with your body
During the moving process
The pressure will gradually disappear
Because of the habit
It also has
certain
If you don't
put the fillings inside
It will deform
So it's better
If there are fillings inside
You can make a fillings inside
After that
We will put the bag
near the back of the body
Then we will
reduce the pressure
This bag can hold
two kids
Yes
But this video
This animation is not
At the beginning
We will go to
the MAKESAMO website
Go to the MAKESAMO website
Just download
Download the animation
The demo I made
You can add subtitles
Because there are many things
Recently, it may be later to post
Then you can find it
If I on-line live
Then it will be released next week
Then you put the bag
Into the bag
into this bag
Change its physical properties
Shift the density
down
Raising depth
is really easy
Make the bag
Sheet
aku
it will automatically pull up.
The hidden shortcut for the moment is Shift-Q.
And then the elasticity of the branch,
its elasticity ratio is very small,
maybe only 9 or 10,
otherwise it can't be made into a belt like this.
Then let's make the belt of the bag,
which is to draw two rectangles,
and then sew it on top of the bag.
The front and back sides of the two circles of the fillet
are all facing outwards,
because I turned the surface of one of the sheets
at the earliest,
then it will be.
Because the sheet in our general software is like this.
For example, I draw a circle,
right?
Then this sheet,
after we use the outer layer of the column,
will automatically form a sheet close to the original sheet,
and automatically form two sheets of the sewing line,
right?
What about these two sheets?
If you pull them a little further,
and then look at them,
one of them is actually facing outwards,
and the other is facing outwards,
right?
Then we will select this sheet facing outwards,
and then we will select this sheet facing outwards,
and then press the right button to turn it over,
like this.
When they are sewn,
they are facing outwards,
all of these two sheets are facing outwards.
These steps are often used.
Because this way,
we can make sure that the direction of its line of hair is correct.
Then we sew the bag on top.
然后在缝的过程中,我有一头会先缝在这个包包上面,另外一头我会用固定针,然后包带的弯曲强度会被我提高一点,这样能够保证它不会因为拉伸的变形而产生一些,就是这根条子会被拉细。
因为大家可能没有发现啊,在MD里面你是没有办法把一块布料真正的撕裂开的,所以它只会被你的拉伸越拉越长越拉越长越拉越长,对吧?
所以在这样的情况下呢,我们就是有的时候为了防止它被,它因为你的拉伸变细,所以会换成比如说皮革这样,弯曲强度比较高的面料。
之后我们把这个包带和包包一起模拟一下就好了。
它一开始看上去比较不稳定,过一会就好了。
然后呢,大家在做包带的过程中可以先把包带做的比较长一点,然后再一点一点拉。
它的这个两端的这根直线不要用那个
缩放工具去把它 curd the tape YES, yes.
You can also make it shorter.
It's best to choose one edge, and then pull it down, or pull it up,
to make it shorter or longer.
Because if you just pull the whole board,
its grid will be completely re-placed.
Doing this will only make your board more unstable.
So when we are changing the board,
I have talked to you many times,
either you choose the point, and then move the point,
or you choose the edge, and then move the edge.
Try to avoid the whole board being locked,
for example, pull up or pull down.
Because if you do this,
your grid will definitely all change,
and it will change a lot.
Then let's take a look at the animation.
Before we do the animation,
I will put a small ball in first.
This ball is the one we put on the hat,
the one we put on the hat.
Then after we put it in,
we can edit it into a double-edged bag.
I won't tell you,
because when I did it alone,
I found it was very unstable,
so I made it into a double-edged bag.
After we put the ball in the double-edged bag,
we can reduce the transparency of the board we are using.
This way, the ball won't move around,
and it will look like it is sewn together
with the edge of the hat.
Right?
After I have done this operation,
you can see that
if I put the ball directly on these two boards,
whether it is this hat board,
or this board,
it will look like there is a line that will show up.
If you sew a small rectangle here,
and then put the ball on it,
it won't show up.
In this way, the center of the ball is correct,
and it won't move around.
Put the ball on the flat surface where it's correct.
We've learned it, right?
Put what we have learned, on the flat surface.
Okay.
After this,
I'll make an FBX file.
After making the file,
because we have replaced FBX recently,
right?
When we were making hats,
do you remember there was a part
where we used a fixing pin
to fix the cap in the circle?
We have fixed it on the head with a fixing pin, right?
Well, if we change a model now
Is it that we are now導入了一个fbx文件
That's equivalent to changing a model after導入了
Since I changed the model
Then these fixing pins will automatically remove
The status of sticking to the virtual model
So we have to add it back to the virtual model
Just stick it to the virtual model
Let it be fixed on the body of the virtual model
You can understand this
So choose this loop of fixing pins
Ah, let's go first
Because we used to reduce the surface diameter of the virtual model
This will have the effect of the hat sticking to the head
well
So after we changed the virtual model
because
Every virtual model
After being introduced to Marvelous Designer
after being introduced to Marvelous Designer
wait, I want to drink some water
After each virtual model is introduced to Marvelous Designer
Its surface diameter will automatically become 3
So we have to reduce its surface diameter to 0
Otherwise
This hat will be like being fixed in the air
Don't forget to drink a lot of water during the winter, or else the air-conditioning in the office will be too strong, and you will easily have a nosebleed like me.
Everyone, please take care of your health.
After we've finished fixing the surface, we're going to...
I don't know if you noticed this earlier, but after I fixed it to the model, it suddenly fixed to another position.
In this case, we recommend that you
put the hat on the other side,
and freeze the two panels first,
so that the two panels are close to your head.
It will be better.
After that, you can fix it to the model.
After changing the model, there are some panels that will always have uneven surface.
Then you first let them simulate it, understand each other, and then fix the pin to the model.
So the poor Santa Claus, he was stabbed three times by the pin this evening.
And then we'll take it out of the freezer to simulate it.
You have to make sure that all of your panels are basically in a stable state, and then go to the animation.
At the end, we can start recording the animation.
Because the FBX file we just imported has animation.
Right?
Then you can see,
before you record the animation,
you have to pay attention to it first.
Does your animation have this problem?
That is to say, just now,
under this needle,
our virtual model,
its back is actually below the ground of the software.
In this case,
you have to right-click in the 3D window.
Right-click in the 3D window,
there is a simulation attribute.
In the simulation attribute,
you can set the height of the ground to negative.
When you set the height to negative,
our material can be properly simulated.
Otherwise, our ground is conflicted.
If there is a conflict on the ground,
if you record the animation again,
the ground will bounce the material up.
The animation at the beginning of our live broadcast today
is uploaded on Mixamo.
If you haven't seen it yet,
you will see it after we upload the video next week.
Then set the ground height to negative.
After setting it to negative,
you won't have a problem with the material bouncing up.
Because now,
the motion of each needle is very large.
Right?
So,
you see,
if we change one needle,
the animation will be much more convenient.
In this case,
if you record directly in the 3D window,
it will be easy to form
your clothes are not simulated and stable yet,
and the next action will come.
In this case,
it will definitely be unstable when we simulate clothes.
In order to prevent this from happening,
because the motion is too large to modify,
it is unstable.
We need to change the scene time.
This option
set it to the number of times,
set it to, for example, 10 times.
After increasing its value,
the number of needles in the whole scene
will increase.
And the number of seconds you simulate will also increase.
In this case,
the animation you simulate will be more stable.
So,
in a situation like mine,
for example,
where the motion is relatively large,
you must first increase the scene time.
Wait until you have finished recording the animation,
and then you can change it back.
After that,
you just need to click on the record button.
Then,
it will automatically record the animation
in the Marvelous Designer.
You can also change the model of ABC.
As long as you import the model
from Marvelous Designer,
you can change it.
But,
in this case,
you must remember to increase the segment time.
The
amount of time sans ale
Anyway,
10 minutes of recording,
you will see it.
So that's it for today, the first part of the content is almost done
I'll go look for this file for everyone
Can you help me pour some water?
Thank you
I don't drink hot water, I want to drink cold water, thank you
Yes, because I haven't changed the resolution of the simulation to the precision one
If I change it to the precision one, the resolution will be slower
You don't need to pour that much, just pour a little
Thank you, just put it here
I'll drink some water
Every time I drink water, the filter turns off
Can't it be a little more intelligent?
It's funny
This is the final product I recorded
I'll zoom in a little bit
The final result is a very cute effect
But...
But did you notice?
After I finished recording, this hat fell to the front
So when I was making the poster for the promotion
I secretly put it back
I secretly lifted it up and lifted it to the back
Yes
So in fact, as long as you are more stable at the beginning
The back is more stable
And then if you say that this shaking
The board shakes more powerfully
Like the skirt, it shakes more powerfully
If you look at it from the front
At the bottom of the physical properties of the fabric
There is an internal damping
Increase this value will be a little better
Its rebound coefficient is relatively large
It's not easy
There are some movements and other problems